## SUSHANT DESHPANDE

Contact #: 403-606-0862 | E-mail: srdyyc@gmail.com | Location: Calgary, AB, T2L 2L6 Profile Page: https://sushant822.github.io/ | GitHub: https://github.com/sushant822 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sushant-deshpande-09b965139/ Tableau: https://public.tableau.com/profile/sushant6978#!/?newProfile=&activeTab=0

### **Profile:**

Data Visualizer and Full Stack Developer with a background in Mathematics and Computer Science. Graduated from University of Toronto's Data Analytics Bootcamp and Master of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science form University of Lethbridge. Experienced in building statistical, predictive, and machine learning models to solve critical problems. Working knowledge of big data, AWS and PySpark. Team-oriented individual with strengths in interpersonal and communication skills and collaborating across diverse groups.

## **Technical Skills:**

Languages: Python, R, SQL, JavaScript, VBA

Data Visualization: Power BI, Tableau, D3.is, Plot.ly, Leaflet.is, Matplotlib, Seaborn

**SQL:** PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server

Python: PySpark, Pandas, NumPY, SciPy, TensorFlow, Keras, SQLAlchemy, Visual Studio Code, Apache Airflow

Excel: VBA, Macros, Pivot Tables/Charts, Index/Match VLOOKUP

Other: Jupyter Notebook, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Hadoop, Heroku, Google Colab, Bootstrap

## **Projects:**

**Predicting Real Estate** | https://findhouseprice.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/dayothompson/ML\_Project **Summary:** Created a machine learning web app. Collected data form websites, build ETL pipelines to clean and transform the data, created database schemas to store data, built flask app to call and pass the data to frontend, built websites and visualizations based on the data using JavaScript and D3, trained the model in python using machine learning with 76% accuracy based on the data to predict the price of a property and deployed it to the frontend.

- Responsibilities: Created algorithms that scraped Remax and Walk Score websites and collected data. Performed cleanup on this data and analyzed it. Build a Flask app and framed APIs to pass data stored in AWS (S3 bucket) to the Flask app as JSON. Generated visualizations for it using JavaScript, D3 and Leaflet. Constructed a machine model using Natural Language Processing and TensorFlow with more than 76% accuracy and deployed it successfully to website. Constantly working on tuning the model to improve its accuracy.
- Number of team members: Four

**JavaScript Project** | https://github.com/sushant822/javascript\_project

**Summary:** Created a Flask app that will read data stored in SQL Database and pass it as a JSON file to the frontend. Build various visualizations using JavaScript, D3 and Leaflet.

- Responsibilities: Created algorithms that scraped Remax and Walk Score websites and collected data. Performed cleanup on this data and stored it in SQL Database. Created a Flask app and build APIs to pass data stored in SQL and NoSQL Database to the Flask app as JSON. Generated visualizations for it using JavaScript, D3 and Leaflet.
- Number of team members: Four

**ETL Project** | https://github.com/sushant822/etl project

**Summary:** Web scraped Remax and Walk Score websites for house listings and walk, bike and transit score respectively. Cleaned the data, stored it SQL Databases and wrote queries and procedures to transform and load the data to frontend.

- **Responsibilities:** Created algorithms that scraped Remax website, collected data and performed data cleanup. Wrote SQL queries and procedures to transform and load the data.
- Number of team members: Four

**COVID-19 Research |** https://github.com/sushant822/COVID-19

**Summary:** This project sets out to answer 4 main questions: who was affected by the virus, which regions in Ontario were affected most, how was the virus contracted, and does weather conditions play a role in the spread of this virus in Toronto?

- Responsibilities: Analyzed the data and created powerful visualizations in Python using various libraries for it thereby
  making the data tell a visual story.
- Number of team members: Three

# **Professional Experience:**

**Data Visualizer/Full Stack Developer,** Weigl Educational Publishers Ltd. – Canada May 2016 – Present **Key achievements:** 

- Attained 90% on yearly review and completed all projects within the set deadlines.
- Achieved 20% better results by providing actionable insights through data analysis and visualization.
- Supervised a team of 6 intern students every summer.

### Responsibilities:

- Collected data from different sources (CSV, JSON, SQL Database, web, etc.), cleaned and analyzed it (using ETL processes) and created powerful visualizations and infographics.
- Analyzed structured and unstructured data to identify problems and organize findings to translate into actionable insights using innovative techniques.
- Visualized sales and production data in Tableau, generated reports, created dashboards using JavaScript, Leaflet and D3 and made presentations to be delivered to sales and management teams.
- Working on creating a full stack solution to build and deploy a model that can predict student grades based on their past performance.

# **Web Designer,** AXON Data – India May 2013 – April 2016 **Key achievements:**

- Handled web design of 75% of client projects.
- Increased customer retention by 18%.

#### Responsibilities:

- Designed website layout/user interface by using standard HTML/CSS/Bootstrap practices.
- Integrated data from various back-end services and SQL Database.
- Created custom graphics for clients with more than 90% client satisfaction score.

# **Web Developer,** Weigl Educational Publishers Ltd. – Canada July 2010 – April 2013 **Key achievements:**

- Launched a new product (Digital Media Enhanced Books) within the set deadline.
- Achieved 25% increase in sales by designing and developing digital media for printed books.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Designed and developed websites using CSS, HTML5, WordPress and Magento.
- Designed and developed Flash activities, Flipbooks, ReadAlongs and audiobooks using ActionScript 3 and HTML5.
- Developed and maintained SQL Database with inventory of books.

### **Education:**

### **Data Analytics Bootcamp, Canada**

University of Toronto

### Masters of Science (M.Sc.), Canada

Masters of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science (Linear Algebra and Combinatory Logic); University of Lethbridge

### Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science; Rajiv Gandhi Technical University

### Awards:

- Awarded with University of Lethbridge Scholarship for getting A grade in Lambda Calculus course.
- Awarded with University of Lethbridge International Research Award for performing outstanding research in the field of Lambda Calculus and Combinatory Logic.
- Consistently recognized by supervisor for demonstrating excellent teamwork and strategic thinking skills.
- Graduated Data Analytics from the University of Toronto with an A+ grade.

### **Publications:**

- A new program in combinatory logic equivalent to  $\lambda\beta$ -reduction.
- Contributed significantly in chapters 'The undecidability theorem' and 'Correspondence between λ and CL' of Lambda-Calculus and Combinators: An Introduction.